Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ dheerumundluru (LinkedIn) www.semanticsquare.com (Company)

Top Skills

Java EE (Spring & Hibernate)
Design Patterns
Java EE (Spring)

Honors-Awards

Certificate of Appreciation

Publications

Automatically Constructing Wrappers for Effective and Efficient Web Information Extraction

Experiences in Crawling Deep Web in the Context of Local Search

Automatically Mining Result Records from Search Engine Response Pages

Automatically Extracting Web Data Records

Dheeru Mundluru, Ph.D.

Founder & CTO at Semantic Square | 125k+ Students | Top-rated Instructor on Udemy

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Summary

I am the founder of Semantic Square (www.semanticsquare.com)
- an EdTech firm offering World-class, industry-oriented online
Software Engineering programs. Based on a unique teaching
philosophy, Semantic Square's mission is to build Complete &
Industry-Ready Engineers with skills on par with engineers at top
engineering teams. Programs are extremely in-depth, highly inspiring
and very practical emphasizing best practices, design principles
& design patterns. As founder I was instrumental in building its
flagship 'Java In-Depth' Master Course whose content is used by
over 100,000 students from 170+ countries including professionals
from companies like IBM & TCS and students from universities such
as Cornell, MIT, and IIT. Apart from this, I've also created in-depth
courses on Design Patterns, Functional-style Programming in Java,
and Java Modularity.

I've a strong background in Software Design & Engineering, Web Data Mining, and Information Retrieval. I'm passionate about building well-designed software and highly inspiring & in-depth courses within these domains. Prior to my current gig, I've worked for several years as a Research Engineer in Silicon Valley & Southern California developing complex Web data mining & integration software. I've also published and presented half-a-dozen research papers at top conferences & workshops such as International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM) and Geographic Information Retrieval (GIR).

Reviews on My Work:

"One of the best courses I have taken on coding in general! On par with courses you can take from Stanford Engineering Everywhere."

"This is hands down the greatest online course I've ever taken ... I am now a data engineer and this course is one of the biggest catalysts for my transition into tech."

"This is by far the best advanced as well as beginner course I have ever read/seen since Andre LaMothe quit writing."

Top Courses:

Java In-Depth: Become a Complete Java Engineer! www.udemy.com/course/java-in-depth-become-a-complete-javaengineer/

Complete Java Engineer (Extended Version of Udemy Course. Includes Professional Certification)
https://www.semanticsquare.com/courses/complete-java-engineer

Design Patterns, Principles and Best Practices in Java www.semanticsquare.com/courses/design-patterns

Functional-style Programming in Java using Lambdas & Streams www.udemy.com/course/functional-programming-in-java-using-lambdas-and-streams/

A Deep Dive into The Java Platform Module System (JPMS) www.semanticsquare.com/courses/java-platform-module-system

All Courses: www.semanticsquare.com/collections

Experience

Semantic Square
Founder, CTO & Principal Instructor
December 2013 - Present (11 years 6 months)
Hyderabad Area, India

Semantic Square is an EdTech organization offering World-class, industry-oriented online Software Engineering programs. Based on a unique teaching philosophy, Semantic Square's mission is to build Complete & Industry-Ready Engineers. As founder, I was instrumental in building its flagship 'Java In-Depth' Master Course whose content is used by over 100,000 students from 160+ countries including professionals from companies like IBM & TCS and students from universities such as Cornell, MIT, and IIT. The course is

designed around a novel, industry-vetted curriculum with an emphasis on comprehensiveness, practicality and industry-standard best practices and design rules. Apart from this, I have also created in-depth courses on Design Patterns, Functional-style Programming in Java, and Java Modularity. Below are the links to courses and few important testimonials.

Java In-Depth: Become a Complete Java Engineer! www.udemy.com/course/java-in-depth-become-a-complete-java-engineer/

Java In-Depth: The Master Course (Extended Version of Udemy Course. Includes Professional Certification)
www.semanticsquare.com/courses/java-in-depth

Explore All Courses: www.semanticsquare.com/collections

Few Testimonials:

"One of the best courses I have taken on coding in general! On par with courses you can take from Stanford Engineering Everywhere."

"This is hands down the greatest online course I've ever taken ... I am now a data engineer and this course is one of the biggest catalysts for my transition into tech."

NimbleCommerce
4 years 8 months

Principal Engineer
July 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 2 months)
Santa Clara, CA

As an early member at NimbleCommerce, a leading e-commerce platform for media firms to launch daily deal sites, I was responsible for architecting and implementing some of its core data integration and sales intelligence features. Responsibilities also include creating technical documents, defining product specifications, managing in-house and off-shore engineers, and interacting with over 30 external technical teams to integrate APIs. Following are some of the key components that I was involved in developing:

- Led a small team in conceptualizing and developing Analyzer, a "sales intelligence tool", which helps sales teams to identify top local businesses to partner with. Given a business name and location, the tool analyzes past

sales of the publisher to predict the number of sales that a daily deal from this business can make. Additionally, the tool also displays a dashboard with social data about the business that is extracted from various sources like facebook, yelp, google places, trip advisor, and group on.

- Involved in architecting and implementing several key components in Nimble Network, a marketplace for daily deals, which allows NimbleCommerce clients to: (a) share deals with one another, (b) source deals from and to several external partners (e.g., Signpost, Travel Zoo, Google Offers) via complex and deep API integration, (c) share deals with affiliates via a RESTful API.
- Generated market analysis data in daily deal space by Web data scraping during the initial phase of product launch, which helped sales team in signing-up several major clients
- Implemented a flexible single sign-on framework that enables deal sites to have single sign-on feature.
- Implemented geo-location framework to display the most relevant deals to users.

Data Mining Research Engineer January 2009 - June 2011 (2 years 6 months) Santa Clara. CA

Apart from my contribution's to NimbleCommerce's SaaS platform, I was also involved in developing several key Web data mining algorithms that power IMshopping.com, another social commerce product that was developed at NimbleCommerce. IMshopping is a human-assisted shopping Q&A Website and the algorithms I implemented include: Q&A recommendation engine, Q&A categorization algorithm, user reputation system, a record linkage algorithm for associating products to their reviews on the Web.

Local.com Corporation
Research Scientist
July 2006 - January 2009 (2 years 7 months)
Irvine. California

Designed and implemented innovative algorithms in the areas of structured data extraction, Deep Web crawling, and opinion mining. The Deep Web crawling project enabled Local.com to significantly enrich its existing business data by crawling high-quality structured data (e.g., ratings & reviews) from the Deep Web.

Webscalers

Software Engineer (Intern)

May 2004 - August 2004 (4 months)

Responsible for developing automated tools for evaluating the performance of SELEGO, which is a unique metasearch engine that allows users to construct their own metasearch engines on-demand.

Thought Creek Software Engineer (Intern) June 2002 - August 2002 (3 months)

Santa Clara, California

Developed a flexible Web-based, wireless application for venue/event management that can be deployed at industry trade shows, museums, etc. Instrumental in developing the complete system successfully in less than 3 months.

Education

University of Louisiana at Lafayette

Ph.D., Computer Science · (2003 - 2008)

University of Louisiana at Lafayette

MS, Computer Science · (2000 - 2003)

University of Madras

BE, Computer Science and Engineering · (1996 - 2000)